Sunil Prakash

+65 84685270 ~ sunil@sunilprakash.com ~ #02-09, Kembangan, Singapore, 418924

Summary

Expertise in Data Science and Machin Learning Skills like Regression, SVM, Neural Networks, Statistical Learning, hypothesis testing, IBM SPSS, JMP.

Expertise with R and Python language for Machine Learning and Visualization.

Worked on Different Visualizations and Analytics using Tableau, gglpot, matplotlib, PoweBI, D3.js

Worked on Big Data Analysis and Platform, Apache Spark, Hbase. and Oracle, MongoDB.

Skilled with Data Analytics and Statistical Modeling for Insight discovery, predictive and descriptive analysis.

Proficient with Supply chain, and Customer Relationship Management Analytics.

Expert with Web development using Java and JavaScript frameworks like J2EE, Spring framework, AngularJS, ReactJS, Node JS.

Skills

Language	R, Python , C, C++ , Java, Scala, Javascript, Bash Scripting			
Tools / Framewroks	IBM SPSS, JMP, Bayesian Lab, Spark			
Visualization	Tableau, Microsoft Power BI, D3.js			
Web/Mobile	JEE, Spring framework, Struts, Jsp/Servlet, Play framework, SailsJS, HTML5,			
Development	CSS3, Bootstrap, iOS, Android			
Big Data	Hadoop, Apache Spark, Cassandra, Hbase, Oozie			
Middleware	IBM Message Broker, ODM 8.5, Filenet, WPS, IBM MQ, JMS, Mule, Spring			
Servers	Websphere Application Server, Weblogic, Tomcat, Jetty, Apache http server			
Database	Oracle 11g, Postgresql, Mongodb , H2, Mysql			
Testing	Junit, ScalaTest, TestNG, Jasmin, Protractor			
Security/Performance	IBM AppScan, Dynatrace			
CI/Automation	Jenkins, Sonar, Nexus, Serena Deployment Automation, Lisa ITKO			

Education

2017-18	MTech. in Enterprise Bu	usiness Analvtics (EBAC). ISS.	NUS. Singapore

2017 Artificial Intelligence Nanodegree ,Udacity

2007 BE in Computer Science from RGTU, Bhopal, India

2002 12th (Senior Secondary) from BIEC, Patna

2000 10(Secondary) from CBSE Board, Delhi

Experience

Solution Architect | Cognizant Technology Solutions Singapore

August 2012 – January 2017

Project Lead | Syntel Ltd Pune, India / Pittsburgh, USA July 2007 - August 2012

Projects

NUS ISS

Face Recognition and Object Classification — *Internet of things (IOT)*

Real time facial recognition with computer vision and tensor flow. Classification of different objects and text captioning.

Vehicle Crash Prediction — Data and Visual Analytics

Data pre-processing and visualization in R for preliminary investigations. Data modelling and prediction of accidents Naïve Bayes model and Regression

Customer Segmentation and Construct Measure

JMP and R Program to cluster customers using K-mean and Latent Class Analysis. RFM and Quantile Regression.

Stock Price Prediction using PCA and Regression

Utilizing PCA for variable reduction and predicting the stock price and company profit using Logistic Regression.

Cognizant Technology Solutions

January 2015 - January 2017

Workflow Automation

BNP Paribas Wealth Management | Singapore

Skills:

Java, JEE, AngularJS, Spring 4, JMS, MQ, Web services, Grunt, Maven, IBM ODM 8.5, Hibernate, Oracle 11g, IBM Filenet, WebSphere

Description:

Workflow Automation project is the middle layer for many wealth management projects, where it provides an interface for managing workflows for process like customer relationship management, portfolio management and various other processed where it requires to involve case management or human interaction for processes, e.g. Approvals of financial transactions, securities, opening of new relationships etc.

Responsibilities:

- Requirement Gathering, Requirement Analysis, Technical Architecture and Solution Design.
- Performance Analysis of existing modules and fine-tuning for performance and security issues.
- Development of modules, setting up frameworks for new modules / projects within same domain.
- Code Review and technical process design from detailed functional requirements.
- · Establishing and Supporting Continuous Delivery Platform by automating deployment process

M-Banking (Mobile Banking) BNP Paribas Wealth Management | Singapore

February 2014 - March 2015

Java, JEE, Angular JS, Spring Integration, Web services, Grunt, Maven, IBM Worklight, Cordova, Android, iOS

Description:

mBanking is the mobile interface for eConnect, Pearl application which allows to manage all the assets and liabilities, view all financial transactions. It enables consumer to perform portfolio analysis, analysis of international financial transactions.

Responsibilities:

- Technical Architecture design of application.
- Working with UI developers and MOA's to reduce the gap during requirement analysis.
- Mentoring Developers and Conduct trainings on AngularJS and Spring
- Profiling and managing provision profiles for iOS and testing devices.
- Developing Hybrid mobile application using Cordova on Worklight platform

• Enabling Continuous Integration and automated deployment of nightly builds.

UCard (EFS-EBT)

August 2012 – January 2015

JPMorgan and Chase | Pune ,India

Role: Solution Architect

Java, JEE, Spring Freamework, Tandem OS, ODS, Hadoop, Cassandra, Apache Sqoop, Mule ESB, Scala

Description:

Ucard center is the one card implementation for the EFS EBT implementation for states like Utah, Oregon, Texas etc. The state issues card to unemployed or below poverty line people as the aided benefit by the state and federal government.

Responsibilities:

- Technical Architecture design of application.
- Proving Solutions for various design challenges
- Monitoring performance with Dynatrace and optimizing application
- Developing Mapreduce and Report generations using queries
- Code Review and Mentoring Developers
- Working with onsite delivery team to ensure efficient delivery
- Troubleshooting production issues and bugs reported by QA team.
- Consultant to various other applications for any challenges
- Creating Development and Deployment Guidelines and Standards

HealthCare Advantage (HCA)

PNC Bank | Pittsburgh, PA, USA

Senior Developer

July 2007 – July 2015

Java, JEE, Spring Framework, Ibatis, WPS, IBM Message Broker, Oracle, Ant, Maven, Jsp, Servlet, IBM MQ Series, JMS, JQuery

Description:

PNC Bank is the third largest Bank in United State after recent acquisitions. The HealthCare Advantage is the ambitious project of PNC Bank to provide its services in the Healthcare Business to the client with their best in market practices.

Healthcare Advantage is a Clearing House, which accepts the HIPPA transitions from the client payer/provide/other CH and correct/optimize using various services, and finally submits to the receiver. EDI Transactions which HCA Provides the implementation are 835,837,276,277,270,271,824,TA1, 997,999 and other Non X12 formats like, ACH,Check, Thin File, Medicare etc. Services like Reassociation, Online Eligibility Request and Online Claim Submission makes PNC to lead in the healthcare business.

Responsibilities:

- Closely Working at Client Side to understand requirements and Technical Specifications
- Working as Onsite Counterpart and help offshore for delivery
- Design and Architect the business process into technical flows and UI Screens.
- Leading the team and managing the Sprints as being the Scrum Master.
- Designing and Planning the Sprints with the project backlog.
- Involve in development of modules, unit test creations and Integration testing of functionality.
- Code Review, Code Refactor and Query Optimizations.
- Coordination with Client and Onsite team for planning of development cycle, branch creation,
- Requirement analysis and review of design and process flows.
- Developing the application and mentoring the teammates for J2EE screens and other backend processes using various j2ee and middleware technologies.

Certifications and Awards

Machine Learning Certificate from Stanford University and Coursera

Certified with SCJP 5.0 (Sun Certified Java Programmer) from sun microsystem.

Certified with SCWCD 5.0 (Sun Certified Web Component Developer) from sun microsystem.

Level 1 Business certification in Banking and Healthcare domain.

Smart Techie Award by Cognizant in 2013.

Difference Maker Award by Cognizant in 2015.

Personal Dossier

Good Communication skills ability to multitask, good analytical and problem solving skills, creative.

Hard working, honest and sincere. Possesses the ability to perform under pressure and meet deadlines.

Always keen to learn, my urge for learning things is my greatest strength.

Current Address:

Kembangan Courts, #02-09, 418924, Singapore

Mobile: +65 84685270

Date: July, 2017 Sunil Prakash

Place: Singapore